VINCENT R. SÁNCHEZ

Javascript Engineer

Summary

I am a web developer with a love for building web apps and a passion for using Javascript and web technology to deliver awesome user experiences. Over the course of two years, I have transformed my curiosity for programming into a host of modern web stack knowledge, autodidactically improving my skills by turning ideas into tangible projects. Always hungry to learn more and play with new technology, I am currently learning AngularJS in order to study its approach to MV* architecture, especially as it compares to React.js' simple API and focus on the user interface of web applications.

Web Development Skills

- Comprehensive proficiency coding client- and server-side Javascript.
- Well-versed in interacting with third-party APIs and web services.
- Understanding of the important role software unit testing plays in the development of clean, modular code.
- Seasoned in use of version control (Git) for code management.
- Substantial experience leveraging the power of NPM to build Node.js software out of small, composable modules.
- Familiar with software design patterns and MV* architecture.
- Knowledgeable of current trends and issues in web development.

Experience

National Necrotizing Fasciitis Foundation, Remote

2014 – 2015

Implemented top to bottom overhaul of non-profit organization's website.

Upgraded look and feel of webpage by incorporating responsive design principles and best practices.

Greatly enhanced user experience for company's mobile audience.

U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, New York, NY 2012

Maintained FOIA IMS database using CRUD functionality to handle data entries on pending charges.

Various Non-technical roles, New York, NY

2006 - 2014

Restaurant industry, volunteer work and internships.

Education

John Jay College of Criminal Justice

2005, 2009-2013

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science,

GPA: 3.79, GPA in Major: 3.88

magna cum laude

Senior Thesis: Twitter Interaction Among

R for Regression Analysis

Members of the 113th Congress

Profile Page: https://tdbts.herokuapp.com/

Key Skills

KNOWLEDGE OF

Node.js

• Linux / Ubuntu

Express

Bootstrap

• React.js

jQuery

MongoDB

AJAX

• Git

HTML5 / CSS3

KEY COMPENTENCIES

- An unrelenting drive to write code powering web apps with rich user experiences.
- The boundless curiosity needed to keep up with the break-neck rate of change in the tools and techniques of modern web development.
- The desire to continually improve skills by tackling formidable yet rewarding problems.
- The capacity to thrive both independently and as part of a collaborative team effort.

RECENT PROJECTS / OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

ShopScraper

Single-page web application using Node.js to scrape product data from local grocery stores for increased personal shopping savings. UI built with React.

Tweet Cloud

Web app that uses Twitter API to search tweets, and arranges them into an interactive three-dimensional sphere. Used Bootstrap, AJAX, jQuery, PHP.

NNFF Official Webpage

Took early 2000's style UI/UX and implemented a complete modern restoration using React, Express and Bootstrap.

JsTagSphere

Identified source of bug that prevented proper rendering of content when doctype declared, making cool software impractical for use in HTML5. Fix allowed me to incorporate the code into the Tweet Cloud.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

I have played guitar for 14 years and I love to listen to music, especially hip hop, punk and indie rock. In my free time I enjoy cooking or traveling around the city to try new food.

COMMUNITY PRESENCE

GitHub (tdbts)
Stack Overflow (tdbts)
Twitter (VRSanchez8717)

CONTACT DETAILS

Vincent R. Sánchez 1326 65th Street Brooklyn, NY 11219

T: 347-255-3115 E: VinnySanchez87@gmail.com